RG 004:042, East Hampton Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
East Hampton Probate Court records
1824-1976
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate (East Hampton District)
39 cubic feet
Record books, 1832-1933; Probate files, 1882-1976, bulk 1915-1976.
RG004_042
2011-116, 2011-118, and 2012-045
Historical Note
East Hampton, Middlesex County, Town established in October 1767, Parent Town: Middletown, Name of town was Chatham until 1915
The Chatham Probate District was constituted June 1, 1824, from the Middletown and East Haddam Probate Districts. The Chatham Probate District changed its name to the East Hampton Probate District in 1921. The East Hampton Probate District merged with the East Haddam, Marlborough and Portland Probate Districts on January 5, 2011 to create the Region #14 Probate District which serves the municipalities of East Haddam, East Hampton, Marlborough and Portland.
Town of East Hampton, Probate District chronology:
October 1767 - May 31, 1824, Middletown District (partial)
October 1767 - May 31, 1824, East Haddam District (covering area south of Salmon River)
May 1820-January 4, 2011, East Hampton District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Region # 14 District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Record books:
Accession 2011-116 contains Volumes 1-24, 1824-1919 and 2 unnumbered volumes of bonds, 1880-1918. These are volumes of the Chatham Probate District that held court in Portland.
Accession 2011-118 contains Volumes 1-3, 1915-1933. These are volumes of the Chatham/East Hampton Probate District. The Chatham District was renamed to the East Hampton District in 1921. In 1913 the Portland District was constituted from the Chatham District. The Chatham District had been holding probate court in Portland and that is where the record books were kept. The new Portland District continued the numbering of the original sequence of Chatham volumes. At that time the Chatham, later East Hampton, District began a new sequence of record books starting with Volume 1. Contact the probate court to access record books after Volume 3 in this series.
See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1882-1976, bulk 1915-1976. Most of the probate files of the Chatham Probate District prior to January 6, 1915 are located among the Portland Probate District. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Arrangement
Record books are arranged in two series, each in a different Accession. Accession 2011-116 contains Volumes 1-24, 1824-1919 and 2 unnumbered bond volumes, 1880-1918. Accession 2011-118 contains Volumes 1-3, 1915-1933. See Scope and Content note for explanation.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- East Hampton
Places:
East Hampton (Conn.)
Alternate Creator:
Connecticut. Probate Court (Chatham District)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2011-116, Record books, 1824-1919 and Accession 2011-118, Record books, 1915-1933, and Accession 2012-045, Probate files, 1882-1976, bulk 1915-1976, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-4, 6, 8, 11, 13, 14, 16, 17, 19, 21, 22, 24, 25, 1824-1922, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in Accessions 2011-116 and 2011-118 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 30, 2011. The record books in Accession 2011-116 had previously been stored at the Portland Probate Court.
The probate files in Accession 2012-045 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on May 29, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1824-1919; 13.5 cubic feet (26 volumes); 2011-116
  The spine on all volumes reads: "Chatham Probate Records"
  - Records, 1824-1830 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1830-1842 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1842-1853 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1853-1864 (Volume 4)
  - Decrees, 1855-1870 (Volume 5)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1864-1873 (Volume 6)
  - Decrees, 1870-1877 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1873-1889 (Volume 8)
  - Decrees, 1877-1887 (Volume 9)
  - Decrees, 1887-1892 (Volume 10)
  - Records, 1889-1894 (Volume 11)
  - Decrees, 1892-1898 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1894-1897 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1897-1900 (Volume 14)
  - Decrees, 1898-1904 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1900-1903 (Volume 16)
  - Records, 1903-1905 (Volume 17)
  - Decrees, 1904-1908 (Volume 18)
  - Records, 1905-1908 (Volume 19)
  - Decrees, 1907-1912 (Volume 20)
  - Records, 1908-1910 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1910-1912 (Volume 22)
  - Decrees, 1912-1919 (Volume 23)
  - Records, 1912-1915 (Volume 24)
  - Bonds, 1880-1904 (Volume unnumbered)
  - Bonds, 1904-1918 (Volume unnumbered)
- Record books, 1915-1933; 1.5 cubic feet (3 volumes); 2011-118
  - Records, 1824-1830 (Volume 1)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Decrees, 1915-1924 (Volume 2)
  - Bonds, 1918-1933 (Volume 3)
- Probate files, 1882-1976, bulk 1915-1976; 24 cubic feet; 2012-045
  - Ananonson - Begley (Box 1)
  - Behm - Bromley (Box 2)
  - Brooks - Chapman (Box 3)
  - Charlson - Curtis (Box 4)
  - Dahlquist - Donovan (Box 5)
  - Eaton - Fuller (Box 6)
  - Gallivan - Gustafson (Box 7)
  - Haglund - Hollister (Box 8)
  - Holm - Hyde (Box 9)
  - Ingraham - Kavanaugh (Box 10)
  - Keane - Kuritz (Box 11)
  - Lagerstrom - Lynch (Box 12)
  - Lynch - Morassini (Box 13)
  - Morey - Palumed (Box 14)
  - Paonessa - Quinn (Box 15)
  - Raab - Schwartz (Box 16)
  - Schultz - Standish (Box 17)
  - Staff - Turner (Box 18)
  - Ulm - Westcott (Box 19)
  - Wheaton - Zykowski (Box 20)
  - Trusts (Box 21)
  - Conservators (Box 22)
  - TPO, A - L (Box 23)
  - TPO, M - Z (Box 24)